We are now concluding the course.
نحن الآن نختتم هذه الدورة التدريبية.
Good job on reaching up till here.
أحسنتم صنعًا بتقدمكم حتى هذه النقطة.
Let's do a very high-level recap of what all we've covered in each lesson.
لنقم بتلخيص عالي المستوى لما قمنا بتغطيته في كل درس.
First, we started with an introduction to the course,
أولاً، بدأنا بمقدمة عن الدورة التدريبية
followed by how to create a process to source clients,
متبوعة بكيفية إنشاء عملية للعثور على عملاء،
different avenues available to find clients,
والسبل المختلفة المتاحة للعثور على العملاء،
and also apply to work for them.
وكذلك التقدم للعمل لديهم.
Then when a client shows interest in working with us,
ثم عندما يبدي العميل اهتمامًا بالعمل معنا،
we discussed the importance of a project scope and how to choose a pricing framework.
ناقشنا أهمية نطاق المشروع وكيفية اختيار إطار التسعير.
Then we discussed strategies to manage projects
ثم ناقشنا استراتيجيات إدارة المشاريع
effectively with the mindset of maximizing value for the client.
بشكل فعال مع عقلية تعظيم القيمة للعميل.
Lastly, we discussed how to formally close a project and secure your payment.
وأخيرًا، ناقشنا كيفية إغلاق مشروع رسميًا وتأمين مدفوعاتك.
This marks the end of this course,
هذا يمثل نهاية هذه الدورة،
but let me say something before we take leave.
لكن اسمحوا لي أن أقول شيئًا قبل أن نغادر.
We have gone through a lot of material in this course.
لقد مررنا بالكثير من المواد في هذه الدورة.
I'd say take the guidelines discussed in this course as guidelines,
أود أن أقول تعامل مع الإرشادات التي تمت مناقشتها في هذه الدورة التدريبية كإرشادات
and not hard rules.
وليست قواعد صعبة.
In freelancing, there is no one size that fits all.
في العمل الحر، لا يوجد حجم واحد يناسب الجميع.
You may work with people from different countries and different cultures.
يمكنك العمل مع أشخاص من دول مختلفة وثقافات مختلفة.
As you work with more and more clients,
أثناء عملك مع المزيد والمزيد من العملاء،
you will naturally develop a pattern and intuition to work with clients.
ستقوم بشكل طبيعي بتطوير نمط وحدس للعمل مع العملاء.
I have personally experienced that the power of intuition helps a great deal when it
لقد اختبرت شخصيًا أن قوة الحدس تساعد كثيرًا عندما
comes to decision-making while working with the client much more than in a rule book.
يحين وقت اتخاذ القرار أثناء العمل مع العميل أكثر بكثير من كتاب القواعد.
Trust your gut as you move along,
ثق بحدسك وأنت تمضي قدمًا،
you might be surprised how many times you're right.
قد تتفاجأ بعدد المرات التي كنت فيها على حق.
In the end, don't forget to enjoy while you take this journey.
في النهاية، لا تنس الاستمتاع أثناء القيام بهذه الرحلة.